http://www.deakin.edu.au/students/enrolment-fees-and-money/enrolments/student-information-privacy

Natural disaster grants
Rural Clinical Support Scheme (Nursing and Allied Health)
Rural Clinical Support Scheme (Medicine)
Disability Support
Who can use services?
Navigate
Respect. Now. Always.
Faculty of Business and Law
International study opportunities (Intensive program)
International opportunities
Work Integrated Learning (WIL)
Supervision
What is confirmation?
Information privacy for students
The purpose of this statement is to inform students about the way in which Deakin University manages its students’ personal and health information.You should read this statement in conjunction with the material located on the Privacy Centre. This statement is under continuous review and it is your responsibility to monitor it for changes.Deakin collects, uses and discloses personal and health information to enable it to operate as an innovative and effective educational institution and to provide its students with opportunities and support throughout their student journey.1. Personal and health informationA reference to 'student information' or 'your information' means both personal information, as defined in the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic):information or an opinion (including information or an opinion forming part of a database) that is recorded in any form, whether true or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent, or can reasonably be ascertained, from the information or opinionand health information as defined in the Health Records Act 2001 (Vic)information or an opinion about the physical, mental or psychological health (at any time) of an individual; or a disability (at any time) of an individual; or an individual's expressed wishes about the future provision of health services to him or her; or a health service provided, or to be provided, to an individual - that is also personal information.2. How we collect your informationYour information may be collected by any means, including hard copy, electronic or verbal means. Deakin will, where practicable, collect your information directly from you.
Directly from Students
The University collects your information directly from you when you submit that information in person, in hard copy, electronically or by telephone. Your information may be collected on application forms, web forms, on-line event registration forms, and in materials you submit to the University as part of your studies (e.g. portfolios, assessment materials).
From third parties
In appropriate circumstances, the University collects student information from third parties. The types of third parties from whom Deakin may collect student information include tertiary admission and testing centres, secondary schools, other tertiary institutions, government agencies, referees, clinical/professional placement supervisors, supervisors of experiential learning, employment agencies, professional accreditation and registration bodies, and contracted service providers.
Electronically
Digital tools and resourcesYour information may be collected when you submit forms via the website or when you use digital tools and resources. These may be hosted internally by Deakin or hosted externally by a third party provider, such as FutureLearn and Studiosity. You may also, as part of your unit enrolment, have access to digital learning resources owned and managed by third parties, in which case the provider will share information about your access to those resources and your assessment outcomes with Deakin.Your information may also be collected when Deakin uses its digital tools and resources. For example, your voice and image may be collected during videotaping of lectures or during recording or streaming of on-line tutorials. CCTV cameras around Deakin’s premises may also capture your image.Learning AnalyticsYour access to digital tools and resources creates information about you that the University collects and uses to analyse your learning patterns. The purpose of learning analytics is to allow the University to understand how individuals learn and how you in particular learn, to provide students   with a more personalised learning experience, and to develop teaching and learning environments that enhance the student journey.
3. How we use your personal informationDeakin will use your information to manage and administer all aspects of your progression through your chosen course of study, your participation in the University community, and your access to and use of Deakin’s business and support structures. The following is a non-exhaustive list of the types of uses of your information that you should expect:
Academic Administration
to undertake selection into Deakin courses;to enrol/re-enrol you in Deakin courses and units;to determine your eligibility for scholarships, bursaries and similar awards;for timetabling;to facilitate your study at Deakin and your completion of course requirements;to facilitate your participation in academic exchanges, practical placements, industry-based learning and volunteer opportunities;to assess your academic work and course-related requirements;to monitor your academic progress;for plagiarism detection, using the Turnitin plagiarism detection service;to process your graduation, including publishing your name of student, date of graduation, and award obtained in the graduation booklet, which is a public document. Webcasts of the graduation ceremonies, which include images and voices of individuals, are made publicly available on the same basis;to process changes to your status at Deakin, including intermission, exclusion and withdrawal.
Academic and information services
to provide you with access to and support from Deakin’s information technology services;Deakin’s libraries;CloudDeakin;to register you with third party learning resource providers, for example, publishers providing on-line learning resources licensed to the University.to register you with third parties hosting Deakin course materials such as FutureLearn.
Academic and welfare support
to provide you with access to and support from University services, including Student services;Disability support;Equity and diversity;Tutoring programs, including peer tutoring;Personal Counselling;Health services;Recreational services;Career counselling;Safer communities services;Insurance and travel services;to communicate with you and/or your nominated contact in the event of an emergency (students should notify the person that they have been identified as the designated emergency contact that contact details have been provided to Deakin);
Financial administration
to enable you to pay tuition fees and other charges;to enable you to use your Deakin card for on-campus payments;to enable processing and payment of  scholarships, loans and bursaries;
Administration of campus facilities and services
to provide and manage teaching and learning spaces;to provide and mange on-campus accommodation through Deakin’s wholly owned company, Deakin Residential Services Ltd.;to provide security and parking services;
Security and discipline
to investigate and report on incidents relating to general  misconduct, breach of academic integrity and breach of research integrity;to operate Deakin’s Safer Communities programs;to process complaints and appeals;
Planning and quality assurance
to undertake audit, planning and statistical analysis, benchmarking, quality assurance activities, continuous quality improvement and research (for internal use and for statutory reporting);
Alumni registration
to register you as a member of Deakin’s Alumni (students are encouraged to view the Alumni collection statement;
Communication
to communicate with you throughout your student journey and as a member of the Deakin Alumni community;to make you aware of university news and events;to invite you to participate in surveys or research;to make you aware of opportunities for further study.
Complaints and appeals
To process appeals against University decisions;To investigate and resolve student complaints.
Sharing of your information within University
Student Information collected by one faculty or division may be shared with staff of another faculty or division where legitimately needed to carry out the activities of the University. For example your photograph may be shared within the University to help identify you when you attend classes or access support services.
4. Why we disclose your informationDeakin will disclose your information to the extent necessary to facilitate your progression through your chosen course of study, your participation in the University community and to enable you to access the services and resources provided by the University. It also discloses your information where necessary for the University to carry out its normal functions and activities. The following is a non-exhaustive list of the types of disclosures of your information that you should expect:
Your study
Deakin may disclose your information to the following types of organisation:organisations involved in your study, for example other educational institutions or international academic partners where you are undertaking an academic exchange, cross-institutional study or a program of study offered in cooperation with another educational institution (e.g. a dual or joint degree, a cotutelle program or a program of in-country supervision;organisations providing you with or involved in organising practical placements, industry-based learning, overseas activities or volunteer opportunities;providers of educational resources and services, to enable you to access course-related materials and activities and to take advantage of services provided. An example of such services is Studiosity;third parties hosting and administering Deakin materials on an electronic platform.  An example is FutureLearn, which currently hosts some web-based Deakin units;providers of plagiarism detection services, currently Turnitin;external assessors, where disclosure of your identity is necessary to protect the integrity of the assessment process;the funder or sponsor if you have been awarded a scholarship or your enrolment is sponsored by an employer or third party;your care provider if you are an international student under 18 years of age;your parent or guardian if you are under 18;(i) health care insurance providers if you are an international student for whom Deakin has arranged Overseas Student Health Cover;foreign governments administering student loan schemes for the benefit of students enrolled at Deakin (e.g. the US government FFEL program);Tertiary Admission Centres across Australia;the Golden Key International Honour Society.
Your community
Deakin discloses student information tothe Deakin University Student Association to enable it to communicate with students and to prepare its electoral role;discipline-based student associations (e.g. the Deakin Law Student's Association, Deakin Medical Student's Association and international professional bodies with student branches)its wholly-owned entities where you are using their services, for example Deakin Residential Services Ltd in the case of students living on-campus;organisations undertaking student surveys endorsed by Universities Australia;to its legal and other professional advisors, as required.
Your profession
Deakin discloses student information to accreditation and registration bodies relevant to your program of study to verify your qualifications, professional registration and conduct, and the accreditation of your course.
Deakin’s accreditation
Deakin may disclose student information to the extent necessary to enable it to maintain its accreditation as a university and the registration of its courses with professional regulatory bodies.Deakin may also disclose student information to agencies and organisations undertaking quality assurance and planning activities.  These include government departments and agencies, the Tertiary Education Quality Standards Authority and Universities Australia.
Deakin’s disclosure obligations
Legislation may require Deakin to disclose your information to government departments.  Examples of the departments to which the University may be required to disclose your information are:Department of Education, Skills and Employment,Department of Industry, Innovation and ScienceDepartment of Home Affairs,Centrelink;Australian Tax Office; andVictorian Department of Health, in the case of prescribed communicable diseases.Note: The Higher Education Support Act 2003 (Cth) (HESA) permits the Commonwealth Government to further disclose your information obtained from the University to authorised bodies for the purpose of regulating, undertaking research into and improving higher education in Australia. HESA contains a list of authorised bodies.
Where permitted or required by law
Deakin may disclose student information where permitted by law. Deakin is permitted to disclose personal information to assist law enforcement agencies, to manage a serious and imminent risk to any individual or where there is a risk to public health and safety. Additional information on permitted disclosures is set out in the Privacy and Data Protection act 2014 (Vic) at IPP 2 and in the Health Records Act 2001 at HPP 2.
5. Additional information
Contracted service providers
Deakin engages consultants and contractors to perform services on its behalf, (e.g. Digitary Australia Pty Ltd, which has been engaged Deakin University to operate the Digital Student Data Network and to provide secure digital documents to authorised recipients).As such, service providers may have access to or create student information Deakin enters into contracts with the service provider that contain appropriate privacy protections.If you provide personal information directly to a contracted service provider, it is your responsibility to review their terms of service and privacy statement. For example, Deakin uses Eventbrite to schedule and arrange ticketing for Deakin-sponsored events.
Lectures and tutorials
If Deakin has recorded lectures or other teaching and learning activities in which your image or voice has been recorded in audiotape, videotape or other media, it may post these on internet sites hosted in or outside of Australia.
Disclosure to family members
Deakin does not disclose your information to members of your family unless authorised by law.  If you want the University to provide information to a family member you should contact the Division of Student Administration and provide written authority for disclosure.
Your Deakin email address
Your Deakin email address and username are provided to you to facilitate your study and your involvement in the University community. Deakin may use your email address or username to register you for services provided by its service providers. This would include, for example, publishers who make learning resources available to Deakin students.Your email and username provide limited personal information and do not disclose other personal information. You must never provide any third party with your password as this, when combined with your username, may allow broader access to your information.
Transfer of your information out of Australia
Deakin may transfer your information outside of Australia to countries that do not have the same levels of privacy protection as apply in Australia. This happens, for example, if you are undertaking a component of your studies through collaboration with an overseas institution, or when Deakin stores information in a cloud-based application located outside of Australia. Deakin will take reasonable steps to ensure the receiving party handles your information in a manner consistent with Australian privacy laws. If Deakin is not satisfied that reasonable privacy protections are in place it will ask for your consent.
Gradsearch
Deakin maintains the Gradsearch services, an online facility that allows third parties to confirm if an individual has received a Deakin award. Gradsearch requires two of three items of identifying information which must be provided to the third party by the student to enable confirmation to be provided.
Consequences of not providing information when requestedThe University will only ask you to provide information that it needs. If you choose not to provide information when requested then it may not be possible for you to be admitted to or enrolled in the University or, if enrolled, you may not be able to access the full range of opportunities, facilities and services available to a member of the Deakin University community.Access to your informationAccess to your personal information is provided through the Freedom of Information Act 1982 (Vic). Administrative units of the University may have processes in place to allow access to documents which are not exempt from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act. You are encouraged to speak with the relevant administrative unit before making a formal request under the Freedom of information Act.Further InformationQuestions about the collection, use and disclosure of student personal information should be directed to the Privacy Officer at +61 3 5227 8524 or privacy@deakin.edu.au.
Enrolment, fees and money
Enrolment
Before you enrol
Plan your course
Course maps
How to enrol
Enrolment codes and terminology
After you've enrolled
Rural Clinical Support Scheme (Nursing and Allied Health)
Rural Clinical Support Scheme (Medicine)
WIL Student Support Scheme
2020 Work Integrated Learning (WIL) Student Support Scheme Application
6,
2019 (10:48am)
Page custodian: University Solicitor
We use cookies to improve your experience. You consent to the use of our cookies if you proceed. Visit our Privacy policy for more information.
OK
